I owe everybody an apology everybody
who's ever used Nano to get started I
owe you an apology I make fun of people
who use Nano I have made fun of people I
actually created a project you can go
find it it's called No Nano and it's
like why learning Nano is bad for
beginners
and I don't think that that's completely
wrong I have had to deal with beginners
who have tried different control X and
control s and control this because of
Nano I I have had to deal with beginners
who have Frozen themselves in their
terminal because they
were they developed the habit of trying
things out with
control because of using Nano that's why
I am overly hostile towards Nano but the
the intent of Nano is fair and solid and
frankly everybody should learn it so in
the holiday boost and in the beginner
boost and in the book um the first
editor any body's going to use from now
on that I teach them is going to be Nano
because it's already on there and you
know if they get if they get dumped in
Kon job like if you use Cron job and you
get dumped in there they're going to
have to use Nano so you have to learn it
it's mandatory learning even if you only
learn it enough to like never use it
again you know um you you just have to
use it
right um and and most beginners won't
know yet to set their editor and set you
know the visual mode and all that stuff
and they haven't installed anything else
so our first EXP experience with editing
a file is setting up westerm as you can
see here which is really fun by the way
because westerm has if you're a absolute
beginner uh or if you're helping an
absolute beginner setting up your
westerm configuration and changing the
theme for example is immediately hot
loaded which is very satisfying
especially if you're just starting out
and you're just starting to realize the
power of the terminal we've been really
having fun with this um and I totally
messed it up i' I've like started
editing this file using VI keys and
totally messing up my lines and
everything so I just want to apologize
to anybody that I've like you know maybe
joked with meanly about using Nano um I
don't like it I hate it but it is a
thing that everybody should learn and
you can't know that you don't like it
unless you try
it so try it try it let that be the
first thing that you use and at least
understand what is going on I mean an
absolute beginner is going to see you
know what does this till the X what does
that even
mean and if somebody was arguing that
that Nano is actually harder for
beginners because they don't know what
they don't know what ti X means they
have no idea what that means so they
still have to learn something right and
um hopefully that they'll figure out
that that means they don't know what a
carrot is if you're an absolute beginner
what the hell is that somebody has to
tell them just like they'd have to tell
them with bi to use I to do insert and
ZZ to escape they have to tell them that
right did I say TIY I meant carrot sorry
I'm I misspoke obviously so uh is there
a way to use down without implementing
oneself with the musical muscle memory
of control hotkey shortcuts I think
there is I think there's a way to to do
that but um to be fair the people that
ended up locking themselves out of their
terminal because you guys just so you
know every default terminal shell bash
Uso and everything is not properly
configured to handle suspend and these
things this state Spec's a really fun
thing it dates way back to the days when
you could overload the TTY printer
teletype um by sending to much stuff so
you were able to like suspend the you
know the printing that's why this what's
there and there if unless you add a
couple specific configuration lines into
your RC files you're going to end up
suspending your terminal and it's just
going to happen I haven't done it in
over a decade since I've added it to my
thing uh but I didn't even learn how to
disable that until I was in my 40s so
you know that's a thing that's the
reason I don't like Nano is because it
teaches people they they learn control X
you know and control C and stuff like
that you know and who knows they might
end up mapping control C to escape and
their VI later